<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
                         <title>HARRY POTTER AND THE GOBLET OF FIRE</title>


                                        Written by

                         <movie_writer>Steven Kloves</movie_writer> 


                                   Based on the book by

                                       J.K. Rowling 


                                      Transcribed by 

   IMSDb.com


                     Please respect the work and keep the credits intact.


               
               We home in on a snake crawling through the undergrowth.

               TITLES<setting>INT. DARK ROOM - NIGHT TIME</setting>

               An old man lights a gas oven with a match, he is preparing food. 
               He notices a light on in the large house opposite, he stops what 
               he's doing and walks to the door.
 
<character>OLD MAN</character>
                         Bloody kids.

               He leaves the house and heads towards the light.

              <setting>EXT. DARKNESS</setting>

               The old man is wandering up to the house carrying a lit torch. 
               He opens the front door, inside is just as dark. He begins climbing 
               the stairs, we hear whispers and hushed voices coming from upstairs. 
               The old man waits outside the room where the conversation is 
               taking place and listens on.
 
<character>WORMTAIL</character>
                         Oh no no no my Lord Voldemort. I only 
                         meant... perhaps if we were to do it 
                         without the boy..
 
<character>VOLDEMORT</character>
                         NO! The boy is everything, it cannot 
                         be done without him and it WILL be done 
                         exactly as I say.
 
<character>UNKNOWN MAN</character>
                         I will not disappoint you my lord.
 
                         
<character>VOLDEMORT</character>
                         Good. First, gather our old comrades. 
                         Send them a sign.
 
               A snake slithers past the old man and into the room. 

<character>VOLDEMORT</character>
                         Nagini tells me the old caretaker is 
                         standing outside the door.
 
               Wormtail stands in the doorway and looks at the old man. The 
               old man looks terrified.
 
<character>VOLDEMORT</character>
                         Step aside so I can give our guest a 
                         proper greeting.
 
               A loud spell is cast and<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> wakes up in a flash of panic.
 
          INT. BEDROOM

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                        <character_ref>Harry</character_ref>!

              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> is flustered and still panicing.

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         Are you alright?

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Hermione. Bad dream. When did you get 
                         here?
 
<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         Just now. You?

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Last night.

               Hermione goes over to Ron's bed.

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         Wake up. Wake up<character_ref>Ronald</character_ref>!

<character>RON</character>
                         Bloody hell.

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         Honestly. Get dressed, and don't go 
                         back to sleep. Come on Ron! Your mother 
                         says breakfast's ready.
 
              <setting>EXT. GRASSLAND</setting>

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Where are we actually going?

<character>RON</character>
                         Don't know. Hey Dad! Where are we going?
 
                         
<character>ARTHUR</character>
                         Haven't the foggiest, keep up!

<character>AMOS</character>
                         Arthur! It's about time son.

<character>ARTHUR</character>
                         Sorry Amos. Some of us had a bit of 
                         a sleepy start. This is Amos Diggory 
                         everyone, he works with me at the ministry. 
                         And this strapping young lad must be 
                         Cedric, am I right?
 
<character>CEDRIC</character>
                         Yes sir. 

<character>AMOS</character>
                         Merlin's beard, you must be <character_ref>Harry Potter</character_ref>.
 
                         
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Yes sir. This way.

<character>AMOS</character>
                         Great great pleasure.

               They shake hands.

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Pleasure to meet you too sir.

               They walk on up the hill.

<character>ARTHUR</character>
                         That's it sir, just over there.

<character>AMOS</character>
                         Shall we? We don't want to be late.
 
                         
               Camera homes in on a boot on top of the hillside.

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Why are they all standing around that 
                         manky old boot?
 
<character>FRED</character>
                         That isn't just any old manky boot mate.
 
                         
<character>GEORGE</character>
                         It's a portkey.

               Everyone is in a circle putting their hands on the boot.

<character>AMOS</character>
                         Time to go. Ready?

<character>HARRY</character>
                         What's a 'portkey'?

<character>AMOS</character>
                         After 3. One... Two...

<character>ARTHUR</character>
                        <character_ref>Harry</character_ref>!

              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> rushes over and puts his hand on the boot.

<character>AMOS</character>
                         Three!

               There's a white flash and suddenly they're all flying through 
               the air. Everyone cheers. 
 
<character>ARTHUR</character>
                         Let go kids!

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         What??

<character>ARTHUR</character>
                         Let! Go!

              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref>, Hermione and the young Weasleys crash to the ground with 
               a thump. Arthur, Amos and Cedric come down more gracefully.
 
               
<character>ARTHUR</character>
                         I bet that cleared your sinuses eh?
 
                         
               Cedric helps<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> to his feet.

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Thanks.

               They walk across the field and we see there's a massive crowd 
               gathered and cheering, tents are set up all over.
 
<character>ARTHUR</character>
                         Well kids, welcome to the Quidditch 
                         World Cup!
 
               They walk into the crowd, taking in the sights. Music is playing 
               and people fly about overhead on brooms. They approach a small 
               tent.
 
<character>AMOS</character>
                         Parting of the waves I think old chap, 
                         see you at the match.
 
               Amos and Cedric separate and walk off.

<character>HARRY</character>
                         See ya later Cedric.

<character>ARTHUR</character>
                         Home sweet home.

              <setting>INT. TENT</setting>

               They enter the tent, the inside is many times bigger than the 
               outside.
 
<character>ARTHUR</character>
                         Girls. Choose a bunk and unpack. Ron, 
                         get out of the kitchen we're all hungry.
 
                         
<character>TWINS</character>
                         Yeah get out of the kitchen Ron.

<character>ARTHUR</character>
                         Feet off the table.

<character>TWINS</character>
                         Feet off the table.

               They take their feet off the table and put them back on as soon 
               as Arthur has walked past.
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         (Smiling) I love magic.

              <setting>EXT. HILLSIDE</setting>

               We pan up the hillside onto a large stadium which seems to have 
               a huge number of floors.
<setting>INT. STADIUM</setting>

               The Weasleys and<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> are finding their seats.

<character>RON</character>
                         Blimey Dad, how far up ARE we?

               Lucius Malfoy and Draco are walking below them.

<character>LUCIUS</character>
                         Well put it this way, if it rains... 
                         you'll be the first to know
 
<character>DRACO</character>
                         Father and I are in the minister's box, 
                         by personal invitation of Cornelius 
                         Fudge himself.
 
<character>LUCIUS</character>
                         Don't boast Draco. There's no need with 
                         these people. Do enjoy yourself won't 
                         you. While you can.
 
               The ceremonies begin. Balloons fly and fireworks go off.

<character>ARTHUR</character>
                         Come on up, take your seats. I told 
                         you these seats would be worth waiting 
                         for.
 
<character>GEORGE</character>
                         Come on!

<character>FRED</character>
                         It's the Irish!

               Five green and white figures fly through the air on their brooms 
               leaving a colored trail behind them. A glittering leprechaun 
               appears in the sky and starts dancing. Everyone is excited.
 
               
<character>GEORGE</character>
                         Here come the Bulgarians!

               Five red figures this time, one of them performs a stunt on his 
               broom. One of them appears on the large screen. The crowd begins 
               to chant 'Krum, Krum, Krum'. 
 
<character>WEASLEYS</character>
                         Krum!!!

<character>GEORGE</character>
                         Yes!

               Viktor Krum waves to the crowd.

<character>ANNOUNCER</character>
                         Good evening! It gives me great pleasure 
                         to welcome each and every one of you 
                         to the final of the 422nd Quidditch 
                         World Cup. Let the match begin!
 
              <setting>INT. TENT</setting>

<character>RON</character>
                         There's no one like Krum. He's like 
                         a bird the way he rides the wind. He's 
                         more than an athlete, he's an artist.
 
                         
               The twins are bumbling about in a comical way muttering 'KRUMMMM'.
 
               
<character>GINNY</character>
                         Think you're in love Ron?

<character>TWINS</character>
                         (Singing) Viktor I love you! Viktor 
                         I do!
 
              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> joins in.

<character>BOYS</character>
                         When we're apart my heart beats only 
                         for youuu!
 
<character>FRED</character>
                         Sounds like the irish have got their 
                         pride on.
 
<character>ARTHUR</character>
                         Stop! Stop it. It's not the irish. We've 
                         gotta get out of here. Now.
 
              <setting>EXT. OUTSIDE THE TENT</setting>

<character>ARTHUR</character>
                         Get back to the portkey everybody, and 
                         stick together. Fred, George... Ginny 
                         is your responsibility.
 
               Some figures in pointed hoods carrying flaming torches are walking 
               across the campsite chanting ominous noises. The crowd is paniced 
               and rushing all over.<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> is trampled unconscious.
 
              <setting>EXT. OUTSIDE - TIME PASSED</setting>

               The crowds have all gone. A man walks through the rubble kicking 
               at things. He casts a spell which causes a bright flash and a 
               large ghostly skull forms in the sky with a snake crawling from 
               it. The man grins evilly, clearly demented.<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> stirs and witnesses 
               the man standing there.<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> runs. The familiar voices of Ron 
               and Hermione are calling for him.
 
<character>RON</character>
                         Been looking for you for ages. Thought 
                         we lost you.
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         What is THAT?

               They look at the monstrous thing in the sky,<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> holds his 
               head in pain. Suddenly they are fired on. 
 
<character>ARTHUR</character>
                         Stop! That's my son.

               Arthur and others approach.

<character>ARTHUR</character>
                         Ron,<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>, Hermione are you alright?
 
                         
<character>BARTY</character>
                         Which of you conjured this?

<character>ARTHUR</character>
                         You can't possibly..

<character>BARTY</character>
                         Do not lie! You have been discovered 
                         at the scene of the crime!
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Crime?

<character>ARTHUR</character>
                         Barty, they're just kids.

<character>HARRY</character>
                         What crime?

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                        <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> it's his mark.

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Those people tonight, in the masks... 
                         they're his too aren't they? they're 
                         his followers. 
 
<character>BARTY</character>
                         Follow me.

<character>HARRY</character>
                         There was a man. Before. There.

<character>BARTY</character>
                         All of you, this way.

<character>ARTHUR</character>
                        <character_ref>Harry</character_ref>, who?

<character>HARRY</character>
                         I dunno. I didn't see his face.

              <setting>INT. TRAIN CARRIAGE</setting>

              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref>, Ron and Hermione are seated on a train. A voice calls 
               out.
 
<character>LADY OFFSCREEN</character>
                         Anything from the trolley? Anything 
                         from the trolley?
 
               The lady appears at their door.

<character>LADY</character>
                         Anything from the trolley dears?

<character>RON</character>
                         Packet of drewbals and a liquorice wand.
 
                         
               Ron sees he hasn't enough money.

<character>RON</character>
                         On second thought, just the drewbals.
 
                         
<character>HARRY</character>
                         It's alright I'll get it.

<character>RON</character>
                         Just the drewbals, thanks.

               Cho Chan walks up to the trolley.

<character>CHO</character>
                         Two pumpkin pasties please.

              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> and Cho look at each other and smile.

<character>CHO</character>
                         Thank you.

<character>LADY</character>
                         Anything sweet for you dear?

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Oh no thank you I'm not hungry.

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         This is horrible, how can the ministry 
                         not know who conjured it. Isn't there 
                         any security or?
 
<character>RON</character>
                         Loads according to Dad, that's what 
                         worried them so much. Happened right 
                         under their noses.
 
               Hermione sees<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> rubbing his head.

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         It's hurting again isn't it, your scar.
 
                         
<character>HARRY</character>
                         I'm fine.

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         You know Sirius will want to hear about 
                         this. What you saw at the world cup, 
                         and the dream.
 
              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> has written a letter, he marks Sirius Black on an envelope 
               and gives it to an owl.
 
              <setting>EXT. HOGWARTS</setting>

               We see four flying horses flying through the air pulling a carriage 
               coming in to land at Hogwarts. The crowds cheer.
 
<character>HAGRID</character>
                         Clear the runway.

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Well there's something you don't see 
                         every day.
 
               A large ship emerges from under the water and approaches too.
 
               
<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         Now we're all settled in and sorted, 
                         I'd like to make an announcement. This 
                         castle will not only be your home this 
                         year but home to some very special guests 
                         as well. You see Hogwarts has been choosen...
 
                         
               A man runs up the aisle limping in a comical way, he whispers 
               something to Dumbledore and leaves in the same fashion.
 
<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         So Hogwarts has been choosen to host 
                         a legendary event. The Tri-Wizard tournament. 
                         Now for those of you who do not know, 
                         the tri-wizard tournament brings together 
                         three schools for a series of magical 
                         contests. From each school a single 
                         contestant is selected to compete. Now 
                         let me be clear, if choosen you stand 
                         alone. And trust me when I say these 
                         contests are not for the faint hearted, 
                         but more of that later. For now please 
                         join me in welcoming the lovely ladies 
                         of the Beauxbatons Academy of magic 
                         and their headmistress Madam Maxime.
 
                         
               A group of girls dressed in blue dance up the aisle and release 
               butterflies into the air. They bow and everyone applauds.
 
<character>STUDENT</character>
                         Blimey, that's one big woman.

<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         And now our friends from the north, 
                         please greet the proud sons of Durmstrang 
                         and the high master Igor Karkaroff.
 
                         
               A series of older boys walk up the aisle brandishing bo staffs, 
               twirling them around and periodically stabbing them into the 
               ground with a spark effect.
 
<character>RON</character>
                         Blimey it's him, Viktor Krum!

               The boys breathe some fire.

<character>IGOR</character>
                         Albus!

<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         Igor.

               They embrace.

              <setting>EXT. HOGWARTS - STORMY - NIGHT</setting>

<character>MADAME MAXIME</character>
                         Professor Dumbledore, my horses have 
                         travelled a long way. They will need 
                         attending to.
 
<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         Not to worry Madame Maxime, our gamekeeper 
                         Hagrid's more than capable of seeing 
                         to them.
 
<character>MADAME MAXIME</character>
                         But you know Monsieur Hagrid, they drink 
                         only single malt whiskey.
 
               The man seated next to Hagrid yelps. Hagrid has stabbed a fork 
               into his hand.
 
<character>MAN</character>
                         You idiot!

              <setting>INT. ASSEMBLY ROOM</setting>

<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         Your attention please! I would like 
                         to say a few words. Eternal glory, that 
                         is what awaits the student who wins 
                         the tri-wizard tournament. But to do 
                         this that student must survive three 
                         tasks. Three extremely dangerous tasks.
 
                         
<character>FRED</character>
                         Wicked.

<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         For this reason the ministry has seen 
                         fit to impose a new rule. To explain 
                         all this we have the head of the department 
                         of international magic cooperation Mister 
                         Bartimus Crouch.
 
               Thunder roars overhead, rain begins leaking through the roof 
               and screams break out. A strange man stands in the doorway, he 
               casts some magic upwards and seals the roof. Peace is restored.
 
               
<character>RON</character>
                         Bloody hell, it's Mad-Eye Moody.

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         Alastor Moody? The aura.

<character>RON</character>
                         He was a catcher. Half the cells in 
                         Azkaban are full thanks to him. He's 
                         supposed to be mad as a hatter though 
                         these days.
 
               This character enters the room and begins walking. We see<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> 
               through his mechanical eye. He limps, breathing heavily as he 
               goes.
 
<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         My dear old friend, thanks for coming.
 
                         
<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         That stupid roof.

               Mad-Eye takes a drink.

<character>PUPIL</character>
                         What's that he's drinking do you suppose?
 
                         
<character>HARRY</character>
                         I don't know but I don't think it's 
                         Pumpkin Juice.
 
<character>BARTY</character>
                         After much deliberation the ministry 
                         has concluded that for their own safety 
                         no student under the age of seventeen 
                         shall be allowed to put forth their 
                         name for the tri-wizard tournament. 
                         This decision is final.
 
               The crowd is unsettled, people are booing.

<character>GEORGE</character>
                         That's rubbish! You don't know what 
                         you're doing!
 
<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         Silence! 

               Dumbledore casts magic over a box which melds into a goblet containing 
               a blue flame.
 
<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         The goblet of fire. Anyone wishing to 
                         submit themselves for the tournament 
                         merely write their name upon a piece 
                         of parchment and throw it in the flame 
                         before this hour on Thursday night. 
                         Do not do so lightly, if choosen there's 
                         no turning back. As from this moment 
                         the tri-wizard tournament has begun.
 
   <setting>INT. ASSEMBLY ROOM - NIGHT</setting>

               We see a suspicious character enter the room where the goblet 
               is still burning and close the door behind him.
 
              <setting>INT. CLASSROOM</setting>

<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         Alastor Moody.

               He writes his name on the board.

<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         Ministry malcontent. And your new defence 
                         against the dark arts teacher. I'm here 
                         because Dumbledore asked me, end of 
                         story, goodbye, the end. Any questions? 
                         When it comes to the dark arts, I believe 
                         in a practical approach. But first, 
                         which of you can tell me how many unforgivable 
                         curses there are?
 
<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         Three sir.

<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         And they are so named?

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         Because they are unforgivable. Use of 
                         any one of them will...
 
<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         Will earn you a one way ticket to Azkaban. 
                         Correct. Now the ministry says you're 
                         too young to see what these curses do. 
                         I say different! You need to know what 
                         you're up against, you need to be prepared, 
                         you need to find somewhere else to put 
                         your chewing gum other than the underside 
                         of your desk Mr Finnigan!
 
<character>PUPIL</character>
                         Aw no way, the old codger can see out 
                         the back of his head.
 
               Mad-Eye throws the chalk in anger.

<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         So, which curse shall we see first? 
                         WEASLEY!
 
<character>RON</character>
                         Yes...

<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         Give us a curse.

<character>RON</character>
                         Well, my dad did tell me about one... 
                         The imperious curse.
 
<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         Ahhh yes, your father would know all 
                         about that. Gave the ministry quite 
                         a bit of grief a few years ago. Perhaps 
                         this will show you why.
 
               Mad-Eye pops open a jar with a spider in it.

<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         Hello. What a little beauty. 

               He uses his wand to send it around the class.

<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         Don't worry. Completely harmless.

               The class is unsettled.

<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         But if she bites... she's lethal!

               Draco laughs.

<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         What are you laughing at?

               Mad-Eye sends the spider onto Draco's face.

<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         Talented isn't she? What shall I have 
                         her do next? Jump out the window? Drown 
                         herself?
 
               Mad-Eye has the spider over a bucket of water, it's wriggling.
 
               
<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         Scores of witches and wizards have claimed 
                         that they only do did you-know-whose 
                         bidding under the influence of the imperious 
                         curse. But here's the rub, how do we 
                         sort out the liars? Another.. another.. 
                         Come on come on. Longbottom is it? Up.
 
                         
               Neville Longbottom stands.

<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         Professor Sprout tells me you have an 
                         aptitude for herbology.
 
<character>NEVILLE</character>
                         There's the um... The cruciatus curse.
 
                         
<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         Correct! Correct! come come. Particularly 
                         nasty. The torture curse.
 
               Mad-Eye begins torturing the spider with magic, it squeals.
 
               
<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         Stop it! Can't you see it's bothering 
                         him, stop it!
 
               Mad-Eye stops. Neville is disturbed. Mad-Eye picks up the spider 
               which is still making a noise.
 
<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         Perhaps you could give us the last unforgivable 
                         curse Miss Granger.
 
               Hermione shakes her head. He casts a spell and the spider disintegrates.
 
               
<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         The killing curse. Only one person is 
                         known to have survived it. And he's 
                         sitting in this room.
 
               He approaches<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>'s desk and takes a drink.

              <setting>INT. STAIRS</setting>

<character>RON</character>
                         Brilliant isn't he! Completely demented 
                         of course. Terrifying to be in the same 
                         room with, he's really BEEN there you 
                         know.
 
<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         There's a reason those curses are unforgivable, 
                         and to perform them in a classroom. 
                         I mean did you see Neville's face.
 
                         
               They see a boy on the stairs facing the window.

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         Neville?

               Mad-Eye approaches Neville and pats him on the shoulder.

<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         Son. You alright?

               Neville nods.

<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         Come on, we'll have a cup of tea. I 
                         want to show you something.
 
              <setting>INT. GOBLET ROOM</setting>

               Older students are placing their names into the flame and others 
               are applauding, Cedric is one of them.
 
<character>RON</character>
                         Eternal glory, be brilliant wouldn't 
                         it? In three years from now we'll be 
                         old enough to be choosen.
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Yeah well rather you than me.

               The twins come up cheering.

<character>GEORGE</character>
                         Thank you thank you, well lads we've 
                         done it.
 
<character>FRED</character>
                         Cooked it up just this morning. 

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         It's not going to work.

<character>FRED</character>
                         Oh yeah? And why's that Granger.

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         You see this? This is an age line. Dumbledore 
                         drew it himself.
 
<character>FRED</character>
                         So?

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         So a genius like Dumbledore couldn't 
                         possibly be fooled by something pathetically 
                         dimwitted such as an age potion.
 
<character>GEORGE</character>
                         That's why it's so brilliant.

<character>GEORGE</character>
                         Ready Fred?

<character>FRED</character>
                         Ready George?

               They jump inside the age line, and cheer. They put their names 
               in the flame and do a high-five. The flame fires up and they're 
               flung across the room onto the floor. When they get up they have 
               full heads of grey hair and beards.
 
<character>GEORGE</character>
                         You said..

               Fred You said..

               They roll around fighting on the floor and the crowd cheer. The 
               room suddenly becomes silent as Viktor Krum walks in and puts 
               his name in the flame. He looks at Hermione and she smiles.
 
          INT. GOBLET ROOM - THURSDAY NIGHT

<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         Sit down please. And now the moment 
                         you've all been waiting for, the champions 
                         selection! 
 
               Dumbledore approaches the blue flame and it glows red. A name 
               comes out. Everyone looks on anxiously.
 
<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         The Durmstrang champion is ... Viktor 
                         Krum!
 
               The Durmstrang crowd cheer. Another name comes out.

<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         The champion from Beauxbatons... Fleur 
                         Delacour
 
               The Beauxbatons girls cheer as Fleur walks up. Another name comes 
               out.
 
<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         The Hogwarts champion... Cedric Diggory.
 
                         
               Hogwarts pupils cheer as Cedric takes the stage.

<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         Excellent! we now have our three champions! 
                         But in the end only one will go down 
                         in history. Only one will hoist this 
                         chalice of champions, this vessel of 
                         victory the tri-wizard cup!
 
               People cheer, but the goblet glows red once more and another 
               name flies out. Dumbledore takes it and reads...
 
<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         <character_ref>Harry Potter</character_ref>. <character_ref>Harry Potter</character_ref>? 

<character>HAGRID</character>
                         No... No.

<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         <character_ref>Harry Potter</character_ref>!

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         Go on<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>.<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> for goodness sake.
 
                         
              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> slowly walks up. Dumbledore gives him the paper. Voices 
               in the crowd shout out.
 
<character>VOICE</character>
                         He's a cheat! He's not even seventeen 
                         yet.
 
              <setting>INT. ROOM</setting>

              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> is in a room with the other champions. Dumbledore bursts 
               in and grabs<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>.
 
<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                        <character_ref>Harry</character_ref>! Did you put your name in the 
                         goblet of fire?
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         No sir.

<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         Did you ask one of the older students 
                         to do it for you?
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         No sir.

<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         You're absolutely sure?

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Yes sir.

<character>MADAME MAXIME</character>
                         Well of course he is lying.

<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         The hell he is. The goblet of fire is 
                         an exceptionally powerful magical object, 
                         only an exceptionally powerful conjurer 
                         could have hoodwinked it. Magic way 
                         beyond the talents of a fourth year.
 
                         
<character>IGOR</character>
                         You seem to have given this a fair bit 
                         of thought Mad-Eye.
 
<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         It was once my job to think as dark 
                         wizards do Karkaroff perhaps you remember?
 
                         
<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         That doesn't help Alastor. Leave this 
                         to you Barty.
 
<character>BARTY</character>
                         The rules are absolute, the goblet of 
                         fire constitutes a binding magical contract. 
                        <character_ref>Mr Potter</character_ref>has no choice, he is as of 
                         tonight... a tri-wizards champion.
 
   <setting>INT. DARKENED TOWER ROOM</setting>

<character>MCGONAGALL</character>
                         This can't go on Albus. First the dark 
                         mark, now this?
 
<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         What do you suggest Minerva?

<character>MCGONAGALL</character>
                         Put an end to it. Don't let <character_ref>Potter</character_ref> compete.
 
                         
<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         You heard Barty the rules are clear.
 
                         
<character>MCGONAGALL</character>
                         Well the devil with Barty and his rules. 
                         And since when did you accomodate them...
 
                         
<character>SEVERUS</character>
                         Master I too find it difficult to believe 
                         this mere coincidence, if we are to 
                         truly discover the meaning of these 
                         events perhaps we should for the time 
                         being let them unfold.
 
<character>MCGONAGALL</character>
                         Do nothing?? Offer him up as bait? <character_ref>Potter</character_ref> 
                         is a boy not a piece of meat.
 
<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         I agree with Severus. Alastor, keep 
                         an eye on<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> will you?
 
<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         I can do that.

<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         Don't let him know though, he must be 
                         anxious enough as it is... knowing what 
                         lies ahead. Then again, we all are.
 
   <setting>INT. BEDROOM</setting>

<character>RON</character>
                         How did you do it?

              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> is silent.

<character>RON</character>
                         Never mind. Doesn't matter. You could 
                         have let your best friend know though.
 
                         
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Let you know what?

<character>RON</character>
                         You know bloody well what.

<character>HARRY</character>
                         I didn't ask for this to happen Ron. 
                         Okay? You're being stupid.
 
<character>RON</character>
                         Yeah that's me,<character_ref>Ron Weasley</character_ref>...<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> 
                         Potter's stupid friend.
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         I didn't put my name in that cup. I 
                         don't WANT eternal glory I just wanna 
                         be.. Look, I don't know what happened 
                         tonight and I don't know why, it just 
                         did ok.
 
<character>RON</character>
                         Piss off.

              <setting>INT. HOGWARTS</setting>

               A woman appears in a puff of smoke. She's well groomed and dressed 
               colorfully.
 
<character>RITA</character>
                         What a charismatic quartet. Hello!
 
                         
               The four tri-wizard champions are stood together in a group. 
               She walks over to them and shakes each of their hands.
 
<character>RITA</character>
                         I'm Rita Skeeter, I write for the daily 
                         prophet. But of course you know that 
                         don't you. It's you we don't know, you're 
                         the news. What quirks lurk beneath those 
                         rosy cheeks? what mysteries do the muscles 
                         mask? does courage lie beneath those 
                         curls? In short, what makes a champion 
                         tick. Me, myself and I want to know. 
                         Not to mention my rabid readers. So, 
                         who's feeling up to sharing? Mmm? Shall 
                         we start with the youngest. Lovely.
 
                         
               She takes<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> by the hand into a closet.

<character>RITA</character>
                         This is cosy.

<character>HARRY</character>
                         It's a broomcupboard.

<character>RITA</character>
                         You should feel right at home then. 
                         Don't mind if I use the quill do you?
 
                         
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Oh, no.

<character>RITA</character>
                         So<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>, here you sit, a mere boy of 
                         twelve..
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         I'm fourteen.

<character>RITA</character>
                         ...about to compete against three students. 
                         Not only vastly more emotionally mature 
                         than yourself but have mastered spells 
                         that you wouldn't attempt in your dizziest 
                         daydreams. Concerned?
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         I dunno I haven't really thought about 
                         it.
 
<character>RITA</character>
                         Course you're not just any ordinary 
                         boy of twelve are you...
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Fourteen.

<character>RITA</character>
                         The story's legend. Do you think it 
                         was the trauma of your past that made 
                         you so keen to enter such a dangerous 
                         tournament.
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         No I didn't enter.

<character>RITA</character>
                         Course you didn't. Everyone loves a 
                         rebel<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>. (to the quill) Scratch 
                         that last. Speaking of your parents, 
                         were they alive, how do you think they'd 
                         feel? proud? or concerned that your 
                         attitude shows at best a pathological 
                         need for attention, at worst a psychotic 
                         deathwish.
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         (looking at the notepad) Hey, my eyes 
                         aren't glistening with the ghosts of 
                         my past. 
 
              <setting>INT. ROOFTOP</setting>

               An owl flies in with a letter for<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>, he takes it and begins 
               to read.
 
<character>SIR</character>
                         (VOICEOVER)<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>. I couldn't risk sending 
                         Edward. It was since the world cup and 
                         the ministry's been intercepting more 
                         and more owls and she's too easily recognised. 
                         We need to talk<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>. Face to face. 
                         Meet me in the Griffindore common room 
                         at one o clock this Saturday night and 
                         make sure you're alone. P.S....
 
               The owl nips<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>'s finger.

<character>HARRY</character>
                         AGH!

<character>SIR</character>
                         (VOICEOVER CONT'D) The bird bites.
 
   <setting>INT. GRIFFINDORE COMMON ROOM</setting>

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Sirius?

              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> picks up a newspaper, the headline reads "THE CHAMPIONS 
               ARE SELECTED" and reads.
 
<character>RITA</character>
                         (VOICEOVER) <character_ref>Harry Potter</character_ref> aged 12, suspect 
                         entrant in the tri-wizard tournament. 
                         His eyes swimming with the ghosts of 
                         his...
 
               Her voice becomes desperate as he crumples up the newspaper and 
               puts it on the fire. The fire flares up a little, a face appears 
               in it.
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Sirius?! How...

<character>SIR</character>
                         I don't have much time<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> so let 
                         me get straight to it. Did you or did 
                         you not put your name into the goblet 
                         of fire?
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         No!

<character>SIR</character>
                         Shh... I had to ask. Now, tell me about 
                         this dream of yours. You mentioned Wormtail 
                         and Voldemort, but who was the third 
                         man in the room?
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         I dunno.

<character>SIR</character>
                         You didn't hear a name?

<character>HARRY</character>
                         No. Umm.. Voldemort was giving him a 
                         job to do. Something important.
 
<character>SIR</character>
                         What was that?

<character>HARRY</character>
                         He wanted... me. I dunno why, but he 
                         was gonna use this man to get to me. 
                         I mean it was only a dream right?
 
                         
<character>SIR</character>
                         Yes. It's just a dream. Look<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>, 
                         the deatheaters at the world cup, your 
                         name rising from that goblet these are 
                         not just coincidences. Hogwarts isn't 
                         safe any more.
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         What are you saying?

<character>SIR</character>
                         I'm saying the devils are inside the 
                         walls. Igor Karkaroff, he was a deatheater. 
                         And no one, no one stops being a deatheater. 
                         Then there's Barty Crouch, heart of 
                         stone, sent his OWN son to Azkaban.
 
                         
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Do you think one of them put my name 
                         in the goblet?
 
<character>SIR</character>
                         I haven't a clue who put your name in 
                         that goblet<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> but whoever did it 
                         is no friend to you. People die in this 
                         tournament.
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         I'm not ready for this Sirius.

<character>SIR</character>
                         You don't have a choice.

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Someone's coming!

<character>SIR</character>
                         Keep your friends close<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>.

               Ron enters the room.

<character>RON</character>
                         Who you talking to?

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Who says I was talking to anyone.

<character>RON</character>
                         I heard voices. 

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Maybe you're imagining things, wouldn't 
                         be the first time.
 
<character>RON</character>
                         You're probably just practicing for 
                         your next interview I expect.
 
               Ron leaves.<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> goes to the fire again but Sirius is gone. 
               The newspaper in the fire has the headline "TEENAGE TRAGEDY".
 
          EXT. LAKESIDE

<character>NEVILLE</character>
                         Amazing. Amazing.

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Neville! You're doing it again!

<character>NEVILLE</character>
                         Oh, right sorry.

<character>HARRY</character>
                         (reading a book) Magical water plants 
                         of the highland Lochs?
 
<character>NEVILLE</character>
                         Moody gave it to me. That day we had 
                         tea.
 
               Neville waves. Hermione and Ron are walking up to them.

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         (Whispering to Ron) We've already been 
                         through enough people why don't you 
                         just go and do it yourself? Ughh. What 
                         do you want me to say again?
 
               Ron whispers some words to Hermione. It's clear Ron and<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> 
               are not on speaking terms.
 
               Hermione walks up to<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>.

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                        <character_ref>Ronald</character_ref> would like me to tell you that 
                         Seamus told him that Dean was told by 
                         Parvati that Hagrid was looking for 
                         you.
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Is that right? Well.... what?

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         Uhhh...

               She walks back to Ron for more whispering and comes back.

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         Dean was told by Parvati that... Please 
                         don't ask me say it again. Hagrid's 
                         looking for you.
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Well you can tell<character_ref>Ronald</character_ref>...

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         I'm NOT an owl!

              <setting>INT. FOREST</setting>

              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> and Hagrid are walking through a dark forest.

<character>HAGRID</character>
                         Did you bring your father's cloak like 
                         I asked you?
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Yeah I brought the cloak. Hagrid where 
                         are we going?
 
<character>HAGRID</character>
                         You'll see soon enough. Pay attention 
                         this is important.
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         What's with the flower? Hagrid have 
                         you combed your hair?
 
               Hagrid is looking more dapper than usual and is carrying a big 
               red flower.
 
<character>HAGRID</character>
                         As a matter of fact I have. You might 
                         like to try the same thing now and again.
 
                         
               We hear animal noises. Madame Maxime calls out to Hagrid.

<character>MADAME MAXIME</character>
                         Hagrid?

<character>HAGRID</character>
                         Oh, the cloak. Put the cloak on.

              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> does as he's told.

<character>HAGRID</character>
                         Bonsoir Olympe.

<character>MADAME MAXIME</character>
                         Oh Hagrid. I thought you weren't coming, 
                         I thought perhaps... you had... forgotten 
                         me.
 
<character>HAGRID</character>
                         Couldn't forget you Olympe.

<character>MADAME MAXIME</character>
                         What is it you want to show me? When 
                         we spoke earlier you sounded so exhilirated.
 
                         
<character>HAGRID</character>
                         You'll be glad you came. Trust me.
 
                         
               A dragon nearby gives a loud roar.

<character>MADAME MAXIME</character>
                         Ahh, c'est magnifique!

               In an opening we see people are running about, dragons are roaring 
               and breathing fire.
 
<character>MADAME MAXIME</character>
                         Can we get closer?

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Dragons? That's the first task? You're 
                         joking.
 
<character>HAGRID</character>
                         Come on<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>. They're seriously misunderstood 
                         creatures. 
 
               A huge flame fires up.

<character>HAGRID</character>
                         Although, I have to admit that horntail 
                         is a right nasty piece of work. Poor 
                         Ron nearly fainted just seeing him you 
                         know.
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Ron was here?

<character>HAGRID</character>
                         Oh sure. His brother Charlie helped 
                         bring him over from Romania. Didn't 
                         Ron tell you that?
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         No he didn't. He didn't tell me a thing.
 
   <setting>EXT. HOGWARTS - DAYTIME</setting>

               We're zoomed in on a badge, it depicts Cedric on a bright yellow 
               background. Then the badge spins and shows<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> on a green background 
               with the words "<character_ref>Potter</character_ref> Stinks" on it. As<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> walks along other 
               pupils aim insults at him saying he stinks. A young boy runs 
               past.
 
<character>BOY</character>
                         Cedric rules!

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Thanks.

              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> gets to a doorway, two pupils stand in his way.

<character>BOY</character>
                         Like the badge?

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Excuse me..

               They laugh,<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> pushes his way through. He approaches Cedric 
               who is standing around with his friends. Cedric's friends hurl 
               off more insults.
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         (to Cedric) Can I have a word?

<character>CEDRIC</character>
                         Alright.

               They walk away some distance.

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Dragons. That's the first task. They've 
                         got one for each of us.
 
<character>CEDRIC</character>
                         Are you serious? And Fleur and Krum, 
                         do they...?
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Yes.

<character>CEDRIC</character>
                         Right. Hey listen, about the badges. 
                         I've asked them not to wear them.
 
                         
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Don't worry about it.

               Ron and Seamus are walking along.<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> approaches them.

<character>HARRY</character>
                         (To Ron) You're a right foul git you 
                         know that?
 
<character>RON</character>
                         You think so?

<character>HARRY</character>
                         I know so.

<character>RON</character>
                         Anything else?

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Yeah. Stay away from me.

<character>RON</character>
                         Fine.

               
               Draco calls out, he's sitting up a tree.

<character>DRACO</character>
                         Why so tense Potter? My father and I 
                         have a bet you see. I don't think you're 
                         gonna last ten minutes in this tournament. 
                         He disagrees. He thinks you won't last 
                         FIVE.
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         I don't give a damn what you or your 
                         father thinks Malfoy. He's vile and 
                         cruel, and you're just pathetic.
 
              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> walks away and Draco angrily tries casting a spell. Mad-Eye 
               appears and quickly turns Malfoy into a ferret.
 
<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         I'll teach you to cast when someone's 
                         back is turned.
 
<character>MCGONAGALL</character>
                         Professor Moody what are you doing?
 
                         
<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         Teaching.

<character>MCGONAGALL</character>
                         Is that a student?

<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         Technically it's a ferret.

               Mad-Eye is making the ferret hover around. He sends it up the 
               trouser leg of one of Draco's friends. He squirms and looks uncomfortable. 
               Everyone else is laughing. Mad-Eye winks to<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> and he laughs. 
               Eventually it comes back out and McGonagall turns Draco back 
               to normal.
 
<character>DRACO</character>
                         My father will hear about this!

<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         Is that a threat! 

               Draco runs away. Mad-Eye shouts after him.

<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         I could tell you stories about your 
                         father that would curl even your greasy 
                         hair boy! It doesn't end here!
 
<character>MCGONAGALL</character>
                         We never use transfigration as a punishment, 
                         surely Dumbledore told you that.
 
<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         He might've mentioned it.

<character>MCGONAGALL</character>
                         Well you will do well to remember it.
 
                         
<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         (To<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>) come with me.

              <setting>INT. MAD-EYE'S ROOM</setting>

               Mad-Eye takes off his prosthetic leg and takes a seat.

<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         That's a foal glass. Lets me keep an 
                         eye on my enemies. If I can see the 
                         whites of their eyes they're standing 
                         right behind me.
 
               A noise emerges from a trunk on the floor and it shakes.

<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         Wouldn't even bother telling you what's 
                         in ther. You wouldn't believe it if 
                         I did. Now... what are you going to 
                         do about your dragon?
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Oh... um... You know I just thought 
                         I'd...
 
<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         Sit. Listen to me Potter. Your pal Diggory, 
                         by your age he could take a whistle 
                         into a watch and have it sing you the 
                         time. Miss Delacour, she's as much a 
                         fairy princess as I am. As for Krum, 
                         his head may be filled with sawdust 
                         but Karkaroff's is NOT. They'll have 
                         a strategy, and you can bet that it'll 
                         play to Krum's strengths. Hmm? Come 
                         on Potter. What are your strengths?
 
                         
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Um... I dunno.. I can fly. I mean I'm 
                         a fair flyer.
 
<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         Better than fair the way I heard it.
 
                         
<character>HARRY</character>
                         But I'm not allowed a broom.

<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         You're allowed a wand.

              <setting>EXT. ARENA - TOURNAMENT STAGE 1</setting>

               The crowds are cheering, people are taking bets.

              <setting>INT. WAITING TENT</setting>

              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> is pacing nervously. Hermione is standing by the tent door 
               whispering in.
 
<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         Pssst!<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>? Is that you?

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Yeah.

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         How are you feeling? OK? The key is 
                         to concentrate. After that you just 
                         have to...
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Battle a dragon.

               Hermione enters the tent and they hug. A bright camera flashes, 
               Rita Skeeter the journalist approaches.
 
<character>RITA</character>
                         Young love! Ohh how.. stirring. If everything 
                         goes unfortunately today you might make 
                         the front page.
 
<character>VIKTOR</character>
                         (To Rita) You have no business here. 
                         This tent is for champions and friends.
 
                         
<character>RITA</character>
                         No matter. We've got what we wanted.
 
                         
               Rita leaves and Dumbledore enters.

<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         Good day champions. Gather round please. 
                         Now you've waited, you've wondered and 
                         at last the moment has arrived. The 
                         moment only four of you can fully appreciate.
 
                         
               The champions gather around him in a circle.

<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         What are you doing here Miss Granger?
 
                         
<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         Oh um.. Sorry I'll just go.

<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         Barty. The bag.

<character>BARTY</character>
                         Champions, in a circle around me. Miss 
                         Delacour over here, Mr Krum, and <character_ref>Potter</character_ref> 
                         over here. Right. Miss Delacour, if 
                         you will...
 
               Barty holds up a bag. Fleur takes out a little green dragon.
 
               
<character>BARTY</character>
                         The welsh green. Mr Krum...

               Viktor takes another out

<character>BARTY</character>
                         The chinese fireball. Oooooh.

               Cedric picks one. 

<character>BARTY</character>
                         The swedish short-snout. Which leaves... 
                         
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         The horntail...

<character>BARTY</character>
                         What's that boy?

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Nothing.

              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> puts his hand in the bag and pulls out the dragon.

<character>BARTY</character>
                         The hungarian horntail. These represent 
                         very real dragons, each of which has 
                         been given a golden egg to protect. 
                         Your objective is simple, collect the 
                         egg. This you must do, for each egg 
                         contains a clue without which you cannot 
                         hope to proceed to the next task. Any 
                         questions?
 
<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         Very well. Good luck champions. Mr Diggory 
                         the sound of the cannon...
 
               The cannon fires immediately.

               Transcribed by IMSDb.com

              <setting>INT. TENT </setting>

              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> is sitting alone nervously.

<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         (VOICEOVER THE LOUDSPEAKER) Three of 
                         our champions have now faced their dragons 
                         and so each one of them will proceed 
                         to the next task. And now our fourth 
                         and final contestant.
 
              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> enters the rocky arena. The crowd are cheering his name. 
               He sees the golden egg sitting alone, he makes a run for it but 
               the dragon appears.<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>'s forced to retreat behind a rock as 
               the dragon flames him.<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> stumbles and falls around the arena.
 
               
<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         Your wand harry! Your wand!

              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> summons a broom. He jumps on and flies off, the dragon 
               gives chase. The dragon bursts through the crowd and they look 
               stunned.
 
              <setting>EXT. HOGWARTS SKY</setting>

              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> is flying at high speed around the Hogwarts buildings. 
               The dragon cuts him off and whips him off his broom, he lands 
               on the roof of Hogwarts, hanging on for dear life. The dragon 
               is clambering across the roof, strewing tiles as it goes.<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> 
               reaches his broom but it's stuck. He jerks it loose and lets 
               go of the roof just in time before the dragon swipes at him. 
               He falls a long way but regains control. He flies on to an area 
               with a bridge, he flies through a gap in the bridge but the dragon 
               crashes into it and falls into the water.
 
              <setting>INT. ARENA</setting>

               The crowds are mostly silent. We see<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> flying towards us 
               and the crowd erupts. He goes straight for the golden egg.
 
          INT. HOGWARTS

              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> is lifting the golden egg, people around him cheering. 
               The Weasly twins have<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> sitting on their shoulders.
 
<character>GEORGE</character>
                         We knew you wouldn't die<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>.

<character>FRED</character>
                         Lose a leg.

<character>GEORGE</character>
                         Or an arm.

<character>FRED</character>
                         Pack it in altogether.

<character>TWINS</character>
                         NEVER!

<character>SEAMUS</character>
                         Go on<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>, what's the clue?

               Seamus hands<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> the golden egg.

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Who wants me to open it? You want me 
                         to open it?
 
               He opens the egg and a loud horrific screech comes out, he closes 
               it again.
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         What the bloody hell was that?

               Ron appears in the doorway.

<character>FRED</character>
                         Alright everyone, go back to your knitting. 
                         This is gonna be uncomfortable enough 
                         without all you nosey sods listening 
                         in.
 
<character>RON</character>
                         I reckon you'd have to be barking mad 
                         to put your own name in the goblet of 
                         fire.
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Caught on have you. Took you long enough.
 
                         
<character>RON</character>
                         Wasn't just me who thought you'd done 
                         it. Everyone was saying it behind your 
                         back.
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Brilliant. That makes me feel loads 
                         better.
 
<character>RON</character>
                         At least I warned you about the dragons.
 
                         
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Hagrid warned me about the dragons.
 
                         
<character>RON</character>
                         Oh no no, I did. Don't you remember? 
                         I told Hermione to tell you that Seamus 
                         told me that Parvati told Dean that 
                         Hagrid was looking for you. Seamus never 
                         actually told me anything, so it was 
                         really me all along. I thought you'd 
                         be alright, you know, after you figured 
                         that out.
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Who could possibly figure that out? 
                         That's completely mental.
 
<character>RON</character>
                         Yeah it is isn't it. Suppose I was a 
                         bit distraught.
 
<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         Boys.

              <setting>INT. CLASSROOM</setting>

              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> is looking at Cho. When she looks back he spills drink 
               from his mouth. They laugh at him.
 
<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         (Reading a newspaper) Look at this! 
                         I can't believe it she's done it again. 
                         Miss Granger a plain but ambitious girl 
                         seems to be developing a taste for famous 
                         wizards. Her latest prey sources report 
                         is none other than the Bulgarian bon-bon 
                         Viktor Krum. No word yet on how<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> 
                         Potter's taking this latest emotional 
                         blow.
 
               A young boy walks up holding a package.

<character>NIGEL</character>
                         Parcel for you Mr Weasley.

<character>RON</character>
                         Thank you Nigel. 

               Nigel is gazing at<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>.

<character>RON</character>
                         Not now Nigel. Later. Go on.

               Nigel leaves.

<character>RON</character>
                         I told him I'd get him<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>'s autograph. 
                         Oh look mum's sent me something. Mum 
                         sent me a dress??
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Well it does match your eyes. Is there 
                         a bonnet?
 
<character>RON</character>
                         Ginny these must be for you.

<character>GINNY</character>
                         I'm not wearing that it's ghastly.
 
                         
               Hermione laughs.

<character>RON</character>
                         What are you on about?

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         They're not for Ginny they're for you! 
                         Dress robes.
 
<character>RON</character>
                         Dress robes? for what?

              <setting>INT. ASSEMBLY ROOM</setting>

<character>MCGONAGALL</character>
                         The yule ball has been a tradition of 
                         the tri-wizard tournament since its 
                         inception. On Christmas eve night we 
                         and our guests gather in the great hall 
                         for well mannered frivolity. As representitives 
                         of the host school I expect each and 
                         every one of you to put your best foot 
                         forward, and I mean this literally because 
                         the yule ball is first and foremost... 
                         a dance. 
 
               Groans emerge from the boys who are listening on. The girls seem 
               a lot more excited.
 
<character>MCGONAGALL</character>
                         Silence. The house of Godrick Griffindore 
                         has commanded the respect of the wizard 
                         world for nearly ten centuries. I will 
                         not have you in the course of a single 
                         evening besmirching that name by behaving 
                         like a babbling, bumbling band of baboons.
 
                         
<character>FRED</character>
                         (Whispering to George) Try saying that 
                         five times faster.
 
               They try.

<character>MCGONAGALL</character>
                         (Continued) Now to dance is to let the 
                         body breathe, inside every girl a secret 
                         swan slumbers longing to burst forth 
                         and take flight.
 
<character>RON</character>
                         (Whispering to Seamus) Something's about 
                         to burst out of Hilary but I don't think 
                         it's a swan.
 
<character>MCGONAGALL</character>
                         Inside every boy a lordly lion prepared 
                         to prance. Mr Weasly, will you join 
                         me.
 
               She grabs Ron and pulls him up to dance. 

<character>MCGONAGALL</character>
                         Now, place your right hand on my waist.
 
                         
<character>RON</character>
                         Where?

<character>MCGONAGALL</character>
                         My waist. 

               He does so and a wolf whistle comes from the crowd.

<character>MCGONAGALL</character>
                         Now bend your arm. Mr Filch...

               The music starts.

<character>MCGONAGALL</character>
                         One two three, one two three, one two 
                         three.
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         (To the Weasly twins) Oi! Never gonna 
                         let him forget this are you?
 
<character>TWINS</character>
                         Never.

<character>MCGONAGALL</character>
                         Everybody come together.

               The girls instantly stand and walk forward, the boys are all 
               still seated.
 
<character>MCGONAGALL</character>
                         Boys, on your feet.

               Neville stands.

              <setting>EXT. HOGWARTS - DAYTIME</setting>

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Why do they always have to travel in 
                         packs? How are you supposed to get one 
                         alone to ask them...
 
<character>RON</character>
                         Blimey<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>, you slayed dragons. If 
                         you can't get a date who can?
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         I think I'd take the dragon right now.
 
                         
               Groups of girls are giving them icy looks and turning their backs.
 
          INT. HOGWARTS

               Hagrid and Madame Maxime are walking together.

<character>HAGRID</character>
                         I take after my mum. Though I didn't 
                         know her very well, she left when I 
                         was about three. No, not the maternal 
                         sort her, broke my dad's heart though. 
                         You know he was a tiny little fellow 
                         my dad, I could pick him up with one 
                         hand by the age of six and put him up 
                         in the dresser.
 
               They laugh together and have a moment.

<character>HAGRID</character>
                         And then he died when I was still in 
                         school. So I had to make me own way 
                         as it were. But enough of me, what about 
                         you!
 
              <setting>EXT. LAKESIDE</setting>

               Viktor Krum is training, a group of girls are following him around.
 
          INT. CLASSROOM

<character>RON</character>
                         This is mad. At this rate we'll be the 
                         only ones in our year without dates.
 
                         
               Severus Snape walks past and slaps Ron over the head. 

<character>RON</character>
                         Well, us and Neville!

<character>HARRY</character>
                         But then again he can take himself.
 
                         
<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         It might interest you to know that Neville's 
                         already got someone.
 
               Ron gasps.

<character>RON</character>
                         Now I'm really depressed.

               Fred hands Ron a note, it reads "GET A MOVE ON OR ALL THE GOOD 
               ONES WILL HAVE GONE!".
 
<character>RON</character>
                         Well Hermione, you're a girl.

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         Oh well spotted.

<character>RON</character>
                         Come on. It's one thing for a bloke 
                         to show up alone. For a girl it's just 
                         sad.
 
<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         I won't be going alone because believe 
                         it or not someone's asked me. And I 
                         said yes.
 
<character>RON</character>
                         Bloody hell.

               Hermione storms off.

<character>RON</character>
                         Look. We've just got to grit our teeth 
                         and do it. Tonight when we get back 
                         to the common room, we'll both have 
                         partners. Agreed?
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Agreed.

              <setting>EXT. HOGWARTS - SNOWY</setting>

              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> is walking up some steps. He reaches the top and bumps 
               into Cho who has come around the corner.
 
<character>CHO</character>
                        <character_ref>Harry</character_ref>!

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Cho!

<character>CHO</character>
                         Watch yourself on the stairs, it's a 
                         bit icey at the top.
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Ok thanks. Cho?

<character>CHO</character>
                         Yes?

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Um. (Mumbling) I just wondered if maybe 
                         you wanted to go to the ball with me?
 
                         
<character>CHO</character>
                         Sorry? I didn't catch that.

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Um. I was just wondering if maybe you 
                         wanted to go to the ball with me.
 
                         
<character>CHO</character>
                         Oh. Um.<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> I'm sorry but someone's 
                         already asked me. And well I've said 
                         I'll go with him.
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Ok. Great. Fine. No problem. Good.
 
                         
<character>CHO</character>
                        <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> I really am sorry.

              <setting>INT. COMMON ROOM</setting>

               Ron is being helped into the room, he looks shaky.

<character>HARRY</character>
                         What happened to you?

<character>GIRL</character>
                         He just asked Fleur Delacour out.

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         What?

<character>HARRY</character>
                         What did she say?

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         No of course.

               Ron shakes his head. 

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         She said yes??

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Don't be silly.

<character>RON</character>
                         There she was walking by. You know I 
                         like it when they walk. I couldn't help 
                         it, it just sort of slipped out.
 
<character>GIRL</character>
                         Actually he sort of screamed at her, 
                         it was a bit frightening.
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         What did you do then?

<character>RON</character>
                         What else? I ran for it. I'm not cut 
                         out for this<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>. I don't know what 
                         got into me.
 
               The Patil twins walk past.

<character>PATILS</character>
                         Hi<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>.

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Hey!

              <setting>INT. DANCEHALL</setting>

               Soft music plays and everyone is well dressed, gathered in the 
               hall. 
 
               
               ELSEWHERE

               Ron is getting dressed in front of a mirror. He looks paniced 
               and uncomfortable in his ridiculous dress robes.
 
<character>RON</character>
                         Bloody hell.

              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> walks in, he's dressed in a more conventional suit.

<character>RON</character>
                         What are those??

<character>HARRY</character>
                         My dress robes.

<character>RON</character>
                         Well they're alright. No lace, no dodgy 
                         little collar. 
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Well I expect yours are more traditional.
 
                         
<character>RON</character>
                         Traditional?? They're ancient! I look 
                         like my great aunt Tessie.
 
               He sniffs at his clothes.

<character>RON</character>
                         I smell like my great aunt Tessie. Murder 
                         me<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>.
 
              <setting>INT. DANCEHALL</setting>

              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> and Ron are walking down the stairs into the hall. Ron 
               is fidgeting with his outfit.
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Leave it alone.

<character>RON</character>
                         Poor kid, bet she's alone in her room 
                         crying her eyes out.
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Who?

<character>RON</character>
                         Hermione of course. Come on<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>, why'd 
                         you think she wouldn't tell us who she's 
                         coming with?
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Because we'd take the mickey out of 
                         her if she did.
 
<character>RON</character>
                         Because nobody asked her. I would have 
                         taken her myself if she weren't so bleeding 
                         proud.
 
               The boys approach the Patil twins.

<character>PARVATI</character>
                         Hello boys. Don't you look...

               She looks at Ron.

<character>PARVATI</character>
                         ... dashing.

<character>MCGONAGALL</character>
                         Here you are Potter. Are you and Miss 
                         Patil ready?
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Ready professor?

<character>MCGONAGALL</character>
                         To dance. It's traditional that the 
                         three champions or in this case four 
                         are the first to dance. Surely I told 
                         you that.
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         No.

<character>MCGONAGALL</character>
                         Oh well now you know. Oh, as for your 
                         Mr Weasly you may proceed into the great 
                         hall with Miss Patil.
 
               Hermione enters the room all dressed up.

<character>PARVATI</character>
                         She looks beautiful.

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Yeah she does.

               Hermione walks down the stairs. Viktor Krum takes her hand and 
               they walk together.
 
<character>PADMA</character>
                         (To Ron) Is that Hermione Granger? With 
                         Viktor Krum??
 
<character>RON</character>
                         No. Absolutely not.

               Loud music plays as the champions head to the dancefloor with 
               their partners.
 
<character>PARVATI</character>
                        <character_ref>Harry</character_ref>. Take my waist.

<character>HARRY</character>
                         What?

<character>PARVATI</character>
                         Now.

               They dance. Soon others are joining in, Dumbledore and McGonagall, 
               Mr Filch and his cat, Hagrid and Madame Maxime. Mad-Eye sits 
               on the sidelines drinking. The scene changes, the music is now 
               rock played by the Weird Sisters fronted by Jarvis Cocker from 
               Pulp. Cool!. The crowd is jumping.<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>, Ron and their dates 
               are sitting some distance away looking miserable. Hermione comes 
               up after a great time with Viktor.
 
<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         Hot isn't it? Viktor's gone to get drinks. 
                         Care to join us?
 
<character>RON</character>
                         No, we'd NOT care to join you and Viktor.
 
                         
<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         What's got your wand in a knot?

<character>RON</character>
                         He's a Durmstrang. You're fraternising 
                         with the enemy.
 
<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         The enemy?? Who was it wanting his autograph? 
                         Besides, the whole point of the tournament 
                         is international magical cooperation, 
                         to make friends.
 
<character>RON</character>
                         Hrmph, I think he's got a bit more than 
                         friendship on his mind.
 
               Hermione walks off.

<character>PADMA</character>
                         Are you going to ask me to dance or 
                         not?
 
<character>RON</character>
                         No.

               
               LATER

<character>RON</character>
                         (To Hermione) He's using you.

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         How dare you! Besides I can take care 
                         of myself.
 
<character>RON</character>
                         Doubt it. He's way too old.

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         What? What? That's what you think?
 
                         
<character>RON</character>
                         Yeah that is what I think.

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         You know the solution then don't you.
 
                         
<character>RON</character>
                         Go on.

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         Next time there's a ball pluck up the 
                         courage and ask me before somebody else 
                         does, and not as a last resort.
 
<character>RON</character>
                         Well that's completely off the point. 
                        <character_ref>Harry</character_ref>...
 
              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> walks up.

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         Where have you been? Nevermind! Off 
                         to bed both of you.
 
              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> and Ron walk away.

<character>RON</character>
                         They get scary when they get older.
 
                         
<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         Ron you spoil everything!

              <setting>INT. BEDROOM</setting>

               NIGHTMARE SEQUENCE

               We're back in the old house. 

<character>VOLDERMORT</character>
                         Let me see it again.

               A sleeve is rolled up and a marking of a skull and snake in on 
               the arm.
 
<character>VOLDEMORT</character>
                         Ah yes, the time is close now.<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>! 
                         At last! Step aside Wormtail so I can 
                         give our guest a proper greeting!
 
                         
              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> wakes up. The floorboards are creaking, someone is walking 
               up to his bed. It's Neville.
 
<character>NEVILLE</character>
                         You alright<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>? I just got in. Me!
 
                         
               He chuckles and dances off.

              <setting>EXT. A BRIDGE OUTSIDE HOGWARTS</setting>

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                        <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> you told me you'd figured the 
                         egg out weeks ago. The task is two days 
                         from now.
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Really? I had no idea. I suppose Viktor's 
                         already figured it out.
 
<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         I wouldn't know, we didn't actually 
                         talk about the tournament. Actually 
                         we didn't really talk at all, Viktor's 
                         more of a physical being. I just mean 
                         he's not particularly... Mostly he watches 
                         me study. It's a bit annoying actually. 
                         You are trying to figure this egg out 
                         aren't you?
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         What's that supposed to mean?

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         I mean these tasks are supposed to test 
                         you, in the most brutal way they're 
                         almost cruel. And um, I'm scared for 
                         you. You got by the dragon mostly on 
                         nerve, I'm not sure it's going to be 
                         enough this time.
 
<character>CEDRIC</character>
                         Hey Potter. 

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Cedric.

<character>CEDRIC</character>
                         How are you?

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Spectacular.

<character>CEDRIC</character>
                         Look I realise I never really thanked 
                         you properly for tipping me off about 
                         those dragons.
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Forget about it. I'm sure you would 
                         have done the same for me.
 
<character>CEDRIC</character>
                         Exactly. You know the prefects bathroom 
                         on the fifth floor?
 
              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> nods.

<character>CEDRIC</character>
                         It's not a bad place for a bath. Just 
                         take your egg and mull things over in 
                         the hot water.
 
              <setting>INT. BATHROOM</setting>

              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> is taking his clothes off, he gets in the bath. He has 
               his golden egg on the side.
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         I must be out of my mind.

               He opens the egg and the horrible screech noise comes out.

<character>MYRTLE</character>
                         I'd try putting it in the water if I 
                         were you.
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Myrtle!

<character>MYRTLE</character>
                         Long time no see.

               The ghostly figure of little Myrtle flies around.

<character>MYRTLE</character>
                         I was circling a blocked drain the other 
                         day and could swear I saw a bit of polyjuice 
                         potion. Not being a bad boy again are 
                         you<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>?
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Polyjuice potion! Kicked the habit. 
                         Myrtle, did you say try putting it in 
                         the water?
 
               Myrtle flies around again and gets in the water.

<character>MYRTLE</character>
                         Well. That's what he did. The other 
                         boy, the handsome one. Cedric.
 
              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> takes the egg and puts it under the water.

<character>MYRTLE</character>
                         Well go on, open it.

              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> does so and goes underwater himself. He hears a voice singing.
 
               
<character>VOICE SINGING</character>
                         Come seek us where our voices sound. 
                         We cannot sing above the ground. An 
                         hour long you'll have to look, to recover 
                         what we took.
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Myrtle, there aren't Merpeople in the 
                         black lake are there?
 
<character>MYRTLE</character>
                         Ahhh, very good. Took Cedric ages to 
                         riddle it out. Almost all the bubbles 
                         were gone...
 
               Myrtle laughs and<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> is embarrassed.

              <setting>INT. COMMON ROOM</setting>

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                        <character_ref>Harry</character_ref>, tell me again.

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Come seek us where our voices sound.
 
                         
<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         The black lake, that's obvious.

<character>HARRY</character>
                         An hour long you'll have to look.

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         Again obvious, though I must admit potentially 
                         problematic 
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Potentially problematic? When was the 
                         last time you held your breath under 
                         the water for an hour Hermione?
 
<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         Look<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>, we can do this. The three 
                         of us can figure it out.
 
               Mad-Eye Moody appears in the doorway.

<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         Hate to break up this scholar session 
                         but Professor McGonagall would like 
                         to see you in her office. Not you Potter, 
                         just Weasly and Granger.
 
<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         But sir, the second task is only hours 
                         away and...
 
<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         Exactly. Presumably <character_ref>Potter</character_ref> is well prepared 
                         by now and could do with a good night's 
                         sleep. Go. Now! Longbottom!
 
               Neville appears from behind a bookcase.

<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         Why don't you help <character_ref>Potter</character_ref> put his books 
                         back.
 
<character>NEVILLE</character>
                         You know, if you're interested in plants 
                         you'd be better with Gorshok's Guide 
                         to Herbology. Do you know there's a 
                         wizard in Nepal whose growing gravity 
                         resistant trees?
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Neville. No offense, but I really don't 
                         care about plants. Now if there's a 
                         Tibetan turnip that will allow me to 
                         breathe underwater for an hour then 
                         great.
 
<character>NEVILLE</character>
                         I don't know about a turnip but you 
                         can always use gilliweed.
 
              <setting>EXT. LAKESIDE</setting>

               The Weasly twins are shouting, busy taking bets.<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> is walking 
               along with Neville, he has some green plantlife in his hand.
 
               
<character>HARRY</character>
                         You're sure about this Neville.

<character>NEVILLE</character>
                         Absolutely.

<character>HARRY</character>
                         For an hour.

<character>NEVILLE</character>
                         Most likely.

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Most likely?

<character>NEVILLE</character>
                         Well there is some debate among herbologists 
                         as to the effects of freshwater versus 
                         saltwater.
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         You're telling me this now? You must 
                         be joking.
 
<character>NEVILLE</character>
                         I just wanted to help.

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Well that makes you sight better than 
                         Ron and Hermione. Where are they anyway?
 
                         
<character>NEVILLE</character>
                         You seem a little tense<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>.

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Do I?

<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         (Over a loudspeaker) Welcome to the 
                         second task. Last night something was 
                         stolen from each of our champions. A 
                         treasure of sorts. These four treasures, 
                         one for each champion, now lie on the 
                         bottom of the black lake. In order to 
                         win each champion need only find their 
                         treasure and return to the surface. 
                         Simple enough. Except for this, they 
                         will have one hour to do so and one 
                         hour only. After that they'll be on 
                         their own.
 
<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         (To<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>) Put that in your mouth.
 
                         
              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> puts the gilliweed in his mouth and starts choking.

<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         (Continued) You may begin at the start 
                         of the cannon.
 
               The cannon fires and the champions enter the water, three of 
               them dive in while<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> is pushed. Underwater the effects of 
               gilliweed take hold,<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>'s hands and feet become webbed. 
 
          EXT. ABOVE WATER

<character>SEAMUS</character>
                         What's the matter with him?

<character>FRIEND</character>
                         I don't know I can't see him.

<character>NEVILLE</character>
                         Oh my god I've killed <character_ref>Harry Potter</character_ref>!
 
                         
              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> flies into the air like a dolphin and the crowd cheer.
 
          EXT. UNDERWATER

              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> swims among the fish and rocks. Singing voices start echoing. 
               We see Fleur get trapped, she screams. 
 
              <setting>EXT. ABOVE WATER</setting>

<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         (Over the loudspeaker) The Beauxbatons 
                         champion Miss Delacour has unfortunately 
                         been forced to retire. She will take 
                         no further part in this task. 
 
              <setting>EXT. UNDERWATER</setting>

              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> is still searching around. He hears muffled screams. He 
               finds Ron, Hermione, Cho Chan and a blonde girl from Beauxbatons 
               tied in place by their ankles. Cedric is there, he takes Cho 
               with him.<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> sets about freeing Ron and Hermione but vicious 
               merpeople appear.
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         But she's my friend too!

<character>MERPERSON</character>
                         Only one.

               What looks like a shark approaches at high speed. We see that 
               it has legs and it's Viktor. He takes Hermione and heads for 
               the surface.<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> frees Ron. 
 
              <setting>EXT. ABOVE WATER</setting>

               Cedric and Cho emerge, the crowd cheers. Viktor and Hermione 
               next, the crows chants 'Krum, Krum, Krum'. The Beauxbatons girls 
               look worried.
 
              <setting>EXT. UNDERWATER</setting>

              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> looks over and sees the blonde girl that Fleur was unable 
               to rescue. He loosens her rope too and starts heading for the 
               surface with the both of them. He's attacked and gets held down, 
               he pushes Ron and the girl towards the surface.
 
              <setting>EXT. ABOVE WATER</setting>

               Ron and the girl come up, they are coughing but safe. They're 
               helped out of the water by a girl from Beauxbatons. Underwater 
              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> casts a spell which propels him towards the surface, he 
               flies out and lands on the decking where the crowd are.
 
<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                        <character_ref>Harry</character_ref>! 

<character>BARTY</character>
                         Get him another towel.

<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         I want all the judges over here now.
 
                         
<character>FLEUR</character>
                         (To<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>) You saved her, even though 
                         she wasn't yours to save. My little 
                         sister!
 
               Fleur kisses<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> on the face.

<character>FLEUR</character>
                         Thank you! And you... (Looks to Ron). 
                         You helped!
 
<character>RON</character>
                         Well... yeah... a bit

               Fleur kisses him too.

<character>RON</character>
                         Merci.

               Hermione comes up to<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> with a towel.

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                        <character_ref>Harry</character_ref>!

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Hermione

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         Are you alright? You must be freezing! 
                         Personally I think you behaved admirably.
 
                         
               Hermione kisses<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> on the head.

<character>HARRY</character>
                         I finished last Hermione.

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         Next to last.

<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         Attention! Attention! The winner is... 
                         Mr Diggory!
 
               Cedric and his friends cheer.

<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         For showing unique command of the bubblehead 
                         shark. The way I see it,<character_ref>Mr Potter</character_ref>would 
                         have finished first had it not been 
                         for his determination to rescue not 
                         only Mr Weasly but the others as well. 
                         We've agreed to award him second place! 
                         For outstanding moral fibre.
 
               
               As they're walking away from the lake<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>'s friends are cheering 
               him.
 
<character>FRED</character>
                         All that moral fibre eh?

<character>RON</character>
                         Blimey even when you go wrong it turns 
                         out right.
 
<character>GEORGE</character>
                         Well done 'moral fibre'.

               
               Barty Crouch is waiting for<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>.

<character>BARTY</character>
                         Congratulations Potter, fine achievement. 
                         Well done boy. I'm sorry we haven't 
                         spoken, after all your story is one 
                         I've heard many times. Quite remarkable. 
                         Tragic of course, to lose one's family. 
                         Never whole again are we? Still, life 
                         goes on. And here we stand. I'm sure 
                         your parents would be very proud today 
                         Potter.
 
               Mad-Eye approaches them.

<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         Bartimus! Not trying to lure <character_ref>Potter</character_ref> 
                         into one of the ministry's summer internships 
                         are we? Last boy who went into the department 
                         of ministries never came out!
 
               Barty walks away from him.

<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         And they say I'm mad.

              <setting>EXT. DARK FOREST</setting>

<character>HAGRID</character>
                         So I remember, I remember when I first 
                         met you all. Biggest bunch of misfits 
                         I've ever set eyes on. Always reminded 
                         me of myself a little. And here we all 
                         are, four years later.
 
<character>RON</character>
                         We're still misfits.

<character>HAGRID</character>
                         Maybe. But we've all got each other, 
                         and<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> of course. Soon to be! The 
                         youngest! Tri-Wizard champion there's 
                         ever been! Hooray!
 
               They walk on singing the Hogwarts song.<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> holds his head 
               in pain. On the ground he sees Barty Crouch laying lifeless.
 
               
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Mr Crouch?

              <setting>INT. HOGWARTS DARK ROOM</setting>

<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         A man has died here. And he won't be 
                         the last, you must take action.
 
<character>FUDGE</character>
                         I will not. In times like these the 
                         wizard world looks to its leaders for 
                         strength Dumbledore.
 
<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         Then for once show them some.

<character>FUDGE</character>
                         The tri-wizard tournament will not be 
                         cancelled. I will not be seen as a coward.
 
                         
<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         But surely that is what's right, no 
                         matter what others think.
 
<character>FUDGE</character>
                         What did you say? What did you say to 
                         me?
 
<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         Excuse me gentlemen, it may interest 
                         you to know that this conversation is 
                         no longer private.
 
               Mad-Eye points to the door.<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> enters.

<character>FUDGE</character>
                        <character_ref>Harry</character_ref>!<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> how good to see you again.
 
                         
<character>HARRY</character>
                         I can come back later Professor.

<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         Oh not necessary<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> the minister 
                         and I are done. I'll be back in a moment. 
                         Minister, after you.<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> do feel free 
                         to indulge in a liquorice snack in my 
                         absence, but I have to warn you they're 
                         a little bit sharp.
 
              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> is left alone in the room. He puts his hand in the snackbowl 
               and takes a handful. It turns into a small creature which nips 
               at his hand.
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Agh!

               A compartment in the wall opens, there's a glowing blue pool 
               of water there. He looks in. He falls and lands in another time 
               and place. It's a courtroom, the walls have a red glow. Dumbledore 
               is seated next to where<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> is.
 
              <setting>INT. COURTROOM</setting>

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Professor?

               The man seated next to Dumbledore speaks.

<character>MAN</character>
                         Professor.

               Dumbledore and the man shake hands. Their handshake goes through 
              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref>'s body, he appears to be some kind of ghost with no presence. 
               Proceedings begin, a cage is raised from inside the floor.
 
               
<character>BARTY</character>
                         Igor Karkaroff, you have been brought 
                         from Azkaban at your own request to 
                         present evidence to this counsel. Should 
                         your testimony prove consequential. 
                         Counsel may be prepared to order your 
                         immediate release. Until such time you 
                         remain in the eyes of the ministry a 
                         convicted deatheater. Do you accept 
                         these terms?
 
<character>IGOR</character>
                         I do sir.

<character>BARTY</character>
                         What do you wish to present?

<character>IGOR</character>
                         I have names sir. There was a Rosier, 
                         Evan Rosier.
 
<character>BARTY</character>
                         Mr Rosier is dead.

<character>IGOR</character>
                         Dead? 

<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         (To Dumbledore) Yeah took a piece of 
                         me with him though didn't he.
 
               Mad-Eye points to his mechanical eye.

<character>IGOR</character>
                         I didn't know.

<character>BARTY</character>
                         If that is all the witness has to offer...
 
                         
<character>IGOR</character>
                         No! No! There was Rookwood, he was a 
                         spy.
 
<character>BARTY</character>
                         Augustus Rookwood? Of the department 
                         of ministries.
 
<character>IGOR</character>
                         Ya ya, the same. He passed information 
                         to you know who from inside the ministry 
                         itself.
 
<character>BARTY</character>
                         Very well. Counsel will deliberate. 
                         In the meantime you will be returned 
                         to Azkaban.
 
<character>IGOR</character>
                         NO! WAIT! PLEASE! I have more. Snape, 
                         Severus Snape.
 
<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         The counsel is very much aware you have 
                         given evidence on this matter. Severus 
                         Snape was indeed a deatheater and prior 
                         to Lord Voldemort's downfall turned 
                         spy for us at great personal risk. Today 
                         he's no more a deatheater than I am.
 
                         
               Igor protests loudly.

<character>IGOR</character>
                         It's a lie! Severus Snape remains faithful 
                         to the dark lord.
 
<character>BARTY</character>
                         Silence!

               Barty hits the gavel repeatedly.

<character>BARTY</character>
                         Unless the witness possesses any name 
                         of genuine consequence this session 
                         is now concluded.
 
<character>IGOR</character>
                         Oh no no no no no. I heard about one 
                         more.
 
<character>BARTY</character>
                         What's that?

<character>IGOR</character>
                         The name...

<character>BARTY</character>
                         Yes?

<character>IGOR</character>
                         I know for a fact this person took part 
                         in the capture, and by means of the 
                         cruciatus curse, torture of the aurer 
                         Frank Longbottom and...
 
<character>BARTY</character>
                         The name! Give me the wretched name!
 
                         
<character>IGOR</character>
                         Barty Crouch! ... Junior.

               Barty Crouch junior begins to run. Mad-Eye zaps him with magic, 
               he falls into the center of the court. The crowd is in uproar. 
               Guards seize Barty junior.
 
<character>BARTY JR</character>
                         Get your hands off me you pathetic little 
                         men. Hello father.
 
<character>BARTY</character>
                         You are no son of mine.

<character>BARTY JR</character>
                         GAHHHH!

              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> steps out of the blue pool and we're back in the darkened 
               room.
 
<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         Curiosity's not a sin<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>, but you 
                         should exercise caution. It's a pensieve, 
                         useful if like me you find your mind 
                         a wee bit stretched. It allows me to 
                         see what small things I've already seen. 
                         You see<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> I've searched and searched 
                         for something, some small detail. Something 
                         I might have overlooked, something that 
                         would explain why these terrible things 
                         have happened. Every time I get close 
                         to an answer it slips away, it's maddedning.
 
                         
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Sir, Mr Crouch's son, what happened 
                         to him?
 
<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         He was sent to Azkaban. Destroyed Barty 
                         to do it. But he had no choice, the 
                         evidence was overwhelming. Why do you 
                         ask?
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         It's just that I had a dream about him. 
                         It was in the summer, before school. 
                         In the dream I was in a house and Voldemort 
                         was there only he wasn't quite human, 
                         and Wormtail was there too and Mr Crouch's 
                         son.
 
<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         Have there been other dreams like this?
 
                         
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Yes. Always the same one. Sir... these 
                         dreams, what I see, you don't think 
                         it's actually happening do you?
 
<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         I think it's unwise for you to linger 
                         over these dreams<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>, I think it's 
                         best that you simply...
 
               Dumbledore puts up his wand and pulls a quivering string of magic 
               out from his head.
 
<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         Cast them away.

              <setting>INT. CORRIDOR</setting>

              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> is walking along, we hear raised voices from inside the 
               herbs store.
 
<character>IGOR</character>
                         It's a sign Severus, you know what it 
                         means as well as I.
 
               The door opens and they see<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>. He looks at them. Igor leaves.
 
               
<character>SEVERUS</character>
                         Potter! What's your hurry? Congratulations, 
                         your performance in the black lake was 
                         inspiring. Gilliweed, am I correct?
 
                         
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Yes sir.

<character>SEVERUS</character>
                         Ingenious. A rather rare herb gilliweed, 
                         not something found in your every day 
                         garden. Nor is this, know what it is?
 
                         
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Bubble juice sir?

<character>SEVERUS</character>
                         Veritaserum. Three drops of this and 
                         you-know-who himself will spill his 
                         darkest secrets. The use of this on 
                         a student is regrettably forbidden, 
                         however should you ever steal from my 
                         personal stores again, my hand might 
                         just slip over your morning pumpkin 
                         juice. 
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         I haven't stolen anything.

<character>SEVERUS</character>
                         Don't lie to me. Gilliweed might be 
                         innocuous, but boomslang skin? lacewing 
                         flies? You and your friends are brewing 
                         polyjuice potion and believe me I'm 
                         going to find out why.
 
               Severus closes the door in<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>'s face.

              <setting>EXT. ARENA</setting>

               Music is playing and a large crowd is gathered. The champions 
               emerge.
 
<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         Earlier today Professor Moody placed 
                         the tri-wizards cup deep within the 
                         maze. Only he knows its exact position. 
                         Now as Mr Diggory...
 
               The crowd cheer on hearing his name.

<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         (continued) and<character_ref>Mr Potter</character_ref>tied for first 
                         position they will be the first to enter 
                         the maze. Followed by Mr Krum...
 
               The bulgarian crowd go nuts.

<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         (continued) The first person to touch 
                         the cup will be the winner. I've instructed 
                         the staff to patrol the perimeter, if 
                         at any point should a contestant wish 
                         to withdraw from the task he or she 
                         need only send up red sparks with their 
                         wands. Contestants, gather round.
 
                         
<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         (To the contestants) In the maze you'll 
                         find not dragons or creatures of the 
                         deep. Instead you'll face something 
                         more challenging. You see, people change 
                         in the maze. Oh find the cup if you 
                         can, but be very weary you could just 
                         lose yourselves along the way.
 
<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         Champions! Prepare yourselves.

               Cedric hugs his father.

<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         On the count of three... ONE...

               The cannon goes off. Mr Filch shrugs comically. Dumbledore groans. 
              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> and Cedric enter the maze through different entrances. 
               The entrance closes up behind<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>. Heavy mist sets in, we pan 
               out to see the maze is many stories tall.<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> starts traversing 
               the maze, creature noises are all around.
 
               Cedric is walking along, the maze walls begin to close in on 
               him. He makes a run for it. Fleur is running around scared, she 
               is attacked and knocked down. Viktor comes along and sees she's 
               unconscious on the ground, he walks on.<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> sees Fleur being 
               swallowed into the undergrowth.
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Fleur? Fleur!

               He's too late she's disappeared. He sends up a red spark into 
               the air. A heavy wind starts blowing, walls are closing in,<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> 
               runs.<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> sees something shining in the distance and he moves 
               towards it Viktor tries to zap him but misses.
 
<character>CEDRIC</character>
                         Get down!

              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> ducks and Viktor gets zapped by Cedric. Cedric runs up 
               and kicks the wand out of Viktor's hand. He points his wand at 
               Viktor's body as if to finish him off,<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> runs up and intervenes.
 
               
<character>HARRY</character>
                         No stop! He's bewitched Cedric.

               They struggle.

<character>CEDRIC</character>
                         Get off me!

<character>HARRY</character>
                         He's bewitched!

               The two of them begin running towards the cup. The undergrowth 
               grabs Cedric and he falls to the ground.<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> looks back. Cedric 
               is pinned down with no means of escape.
 
<character>CEDRIC</character>
                        <character_ref>Harry</character_ref>!<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>!

              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> zaps the plantlife and Cedric wriggles free.<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> helps 
               him up.
 
<character>CEDRIC</character>
                         You know for a moment there I thought 
                         you were gonna let it get me.
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         For a moment so did I.

<character>CEDRIC</character>
                         Some game huh?

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Some game.

               The wind starts blowing again.

<character>CEDRIC</character>
                         Go. Take it, you saved me!

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Together, on three. One, two, three!
 
   <setting>EXT. GRAVEYARD</setting>

              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> and Cedric have ported to a graveyard. 

<character>CEDRIC</character>
                         You ok?

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Yeah, you?

<character>CEDRIC</character>
                         Where are we?

<character>HARRY</character>
                         I've been here before.

<character>CEDRIC</character>
                         It's a portkey.<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> the cup is a portkey.
 
                         
<character>HARRY</character>
                         I've been here before in a dream. Cedric, 
                         we have to get back to the cup? Now!
 
                         
<character>CEDRIC</character>
                         What are you talking about?

              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> lets out a shout and holds his head, he is in pain.

<character>CEDRIC</character>
                         What is it?

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Get back to the cup!

               We see Wormtail and Voldemort nearby. 

<character>CEDRIC</character>
                         Who are you? What do you want?

<character>VOLDEMORT</character>
                         Kill the spare.

               Wormtail casts a spell and kills Cedric.

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Cedric!

               Cedric lays dead on the ground.

               Wormtail pulls<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> closer, a status grabs hold of<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> and 
               traps him.
 
<character>VOLDEMORT</character>
                         Do it, now!

               Wormtail drops something into a cauldron,<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> watches on. 
 
               
<character>WORMTAIL</character>
                         Bones of the father, unwillingly given. 
                         
 
               A bone hovers in the air under Wormtail's control, he drops it 
               into the cauldron.
 
<character>WORMTAIL</character>
                         Flesh of the servent willingly sacrificed. 
                         
 
               He takes a knife and slashes his arm over the cauldron.

<character>WORMTAIL</character>
                         Blood of the enemy forcibly taken.
 
                         
               He takes the knife to<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> and cuts at his arm.<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> shouts. 
               Wormtail takes the knife over to the cauldron and lets the drops 
               fall into it.
 
<character>WORMTAIL</character>
                         The dark lord shall rise again. 

               The cauldron bursts into flame and a reformed Voldemort emerges.
 
               
<character>VOLDEMORT</character>
                         My wand Wormtail.

               Wormtail hands him the wand and bows deeply.

<character>VOLDEMORT</character>
                         Hold out your arm.

<character>WORMTAIL</character>
                         Master. Thank you master.

<character>VOLDEMORT</character>
                         The other arm Wormtail.

               Wormtail looks concerned, but does it anyway. Voldemort sticks 
               the wand into Wormtail's arm. The sky changes, others have been 
               summoned.
 
<character>VOLDEMORT</character>
                         Welcome my friends. Thirty years it's 
                         been, and yet you stand before me as 
                         though it were only yesterday. I confess 
                         myself disappointed, not one of you 
                         tried to find me. 
 
               Voldemort begins slashing angrily at the hooded figures. 

<character>VOLDEMORT</character>
                         Not even you, Lucius. 

<character>LUCIUS</character>
                         My lord. Had I detected any sign or 
                         even a whisper of your whereabouts.
 
                         
<character>VOLDEMORT</character>
                         There were signs my friend, and more 
                         than whispers. 
 
<character>LUCIUS</character>
                         I assure you I never renounced the old 
                         ways. The face I have been obliged to 
                         present each day since your absence, 
                         that was my true mask.
 
<character>WORMTAIL</character>
                         I returned.

<character>VOLDEMORT</character>
                         Out of fear, not loyalty. Still you 
                         have proved yourself useful these past 
                         few months Wormtail.
 
               Voldemort grants Wormtail a new hand.

<character>WORMTAIL</character>
                         Thank you master, thank you.

<character>VOLDEMORT</character>
                         (To Cedric's corpse) Oh, such a handsome 
                         boy. 
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Don't touch him.

              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> struggles to get free.

<character>VOLDEMORT</character>
                        <character_ref>Harry</character_ref>! I'd almost forgotten you were 
                         here. Standing on the bones of my father. 
                         I'd introduce you but word has it you're 
                         almost as famous as me these days. The 
                         boy who lived. How lies have fed your 
                         legend<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>. Shall I reveal what really 
                         happened that night thirteen years ago? 
                         Shall I divulge how I truly lost my 
                         powers? It was love. You see when dear 
                         sweet Lily <character_ref>Potter</character_ref> gave her life for 
                         her only son she provided the ultimate 
                         protection. I could not touch you. It 
                         was old magic, something I should have 
                         forseen. But no matter, no matter. Things 
                         have changed, I can touch you now!
 
                         
               Voldemort puts his hand on<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>'s head and he screams.

<character>VOLDEMORT</character>
                         Astonishing what a few drops of your 
                         blood will do eh<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>? Pick up your 
                         wand Potter. I said pick it up, get 
                         up. Get up! You've been taught how to 
                         duel I presume yes? First we bow to 
                         each other. Come on now<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> the niceties 
                         must be observed, Dumbledore would not 
                         want you to forget your manners now 
                         would he? I said bow!
 
               Voldemort forces<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> to bow with magic.

<character>VOLDEMORT</character>
                         That's better. And now...

               Voldemort casts at<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> and he wriggles in pain.

<character>VOLDEMORT</character>
                         Atta boy<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>, your parents would be 
                         proud. Especially your filthy mongrel 
                         mother. I'm going to kill you<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> 
                         Potter, I'm going to destroy you. After 
                         tonight no one will ever again question 
                         my powers. After tonight if they speak 
                         of you they'll speak only of how you 
                         begged for death, and I being a merciful 
                         lord obliged. Get up.
 
               Voldemort pulls<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> to his feet,<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> begins to move away.
 
               
<character>VOLDEMORT</character>
                         Don't you turn your back on me<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> 
                         <character_ref>Potter</character_ref> I want you to look at me when 
                         I kill you, I want to see the lights 
                         leave your eyes.
 
              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> takes steps toward Voldemort.

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Have it your way.

               They both cast and their streams of magic meet. They both struggle.
 
               
<character>VOLDEMORT</character>
                         Do nothing. He is mine to finish. He's 
                         mine!
 
               Shapes form in the surrounding magical energy. We hear Dumbledore's 
               voice.
 
<character>HARRY</character>'S DAD
                         (voice)<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> when the connection is 
                         broken you must get to the portkey. 
                         We can delay it for a moment to give 
                         you time but only a moment, do you understand?
 
                         
<character>CEDRIC</character>
                         (voice)<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> take my body back will 
                         you? Take my body back to my father.
 
                         
<character>HARRY</character>'S MOTHER
                         (voice) Let go. Sweetheart you're ready. 
                         Let go! Let go!
 
               The connection breaks,<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> runs over to Cedric's body and summons 
               the cup over to them. In an instant the port out. Voldemort looks 
               angry.
 
<character>VOLDEMORT</character>
                         No!

              <setting>EXT. ARENA</setting>

               Back at the arena<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> appears with Cedric's body. The crowd 
               don't understand what has taken place and they all cheer, triumphant 
               music starts to play.<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> weeps on Cedric's body. 
 
<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                        <character_ref>Harry</character_ref>!<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>!

               Dumbledore tries to prize<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> from Cedric's body.

<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         Tell me what happened!

<character>HARRY</character>
                         He's back, he's back! Voldemort's back. 
                         Cedric, he asked me to bring his body 
                         back. I couldn't leave him, not there.
 
                         
<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         It's alright<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>. It's alright, he's 
                         home, you both are.
 
<character>FUDGE</character>
                         Keep everybody in their seats. A boy 
                         has just been killed. The body must 
                         be moved Dumbledore, there are... too 
                         many people.
 
<character>AMOS</character>
                         Let me through! That's my son! My boy!
 
                         
               Amos breaks down wailing. The crowd look on distraught.

              <setting>INT. DARKENED ROOM</setting>

               Mad-Eye Moody enters and closes the door behind him.<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> is 
               in the room still sobbing. They sit. 
 
<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         Are you alright Potter?

              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> nods.

<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         Does it hurt?

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Not so much now.

<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         I'd better take a look at it.

               We see<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>'s arm, it has a skull and snake marking.

<character>HARRY</character>
                         The cup was a portkey. Someone had bewitched 
                         it.
 
<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         What was it like? What was he like?
 
                         
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Who?

<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         The dark lord. What was it like to stand 
                         in his presence?
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         I dunno. It was like I'd fallen into 
                         one of my dreams. One of my nightmares. 
                         
 
               Mad-Eye starts shaking and struggling for air, he reaches for 
               his bottle but it's empty. He rushes to a chest with other bottles 
               and struggles to find one.
 
<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         Were there others? In the graveyard, 
                         were there others?
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Um. I don't think I said anything about 
                         a graveyard Professor.
 
<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         Marvellous creatures dragons aren't 
                         they? Do you think that miserable oaf 
                         would have led you into the woods if 
                         I hadn't suggested it? Do you think 
                         Cedric Diggory would have told you to 
                         hold the egg under the water if I hadn't 
                         have told him first myself? Do you think 
                         Neville Longbottom the witless wonder 
                         could have provided you with gilliweed 
                         if I hadn't have given him the book 
                         that led you straight to it? Huh??
 
                         
<character>HARRY</character>
                         It was you from the beginning. You put 
                         my name in the goblet of fire. You bewitched 
                         Krum. But...
 
               Mad-Eye makes sobbing noises making fun of<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>.

<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         You won because I made it so Potter. 
                         You ended up in that graveyard tonight 
                         because it was meant to be so. And now 
                         the deed is done. The blood that runs 
                         through these veins runs within the 
                         dark lord. Imagine how he will reward 
                         me when he learns that I have once and 
                         for all silenced the great <character_ref>Harry Potter</character_ref>.
 
                         
               A flash of magic occurs and Mad-Eye is knocked into the wall. 
               Dumbledore and Severus come rushing in. Dumbledore takes Mad-Eye 
               by the neck...
 
<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         Severus...

               Severus administers some veritaserum. Mad-Eye wriggles demonically.
 
               
<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         Do you know who I am?

<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         Albus Dumbledore.

<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         Are you Alastor Moody? Are ya?

<character>MAD-EYE</character>
                         No.

<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         Is he in this room? Is he in this room?
 
                         
               We see a nod.

<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                        <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> get away from there!

               Dumbledore approaches the chest. The chest opens, it contains 
               a series of smaller chests. When the final chest is open we see 
               that there's a pit within holding a man the real Alastor Moody.
 
               
<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         Are you alright Alastor?

<character>ALASTOR</character>
                         I'm sorry Albus.

<character>HARRY</character>
                         That's Moody, but then who's...?

               Dumbledore holds up one of Mad-Eye's Bottles.

<character>SEVERUS</character>
                         Polyjuice potion.

<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         Now we know who's been stealing it from 
                         your store Severus.
 
               Dumbledore looks into the pit.

<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         We'll get you up in a minute.

               Alastor Moody groans. The Mad-Eye Moody they have captive in 
               a chair begins to twitch about restlessly making strange noises. 
               He appears to be transforming. He rips off his fake eyepiece 
               which falls on the floor, we see that he's transformed into Barty 
               Crouch Junior.
 
<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         Barty Crouch Junior.

<character>BARTY JR</character>
                         I'll show you mine if you show me yours.
 
                         
               Barty Jr rolls up his sleeve to reveal a skull and snake marking.
 
               
<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         Your arm<character_ref>Harry</character_ref>.

<character>BARTY JR</character>
                         You know what this means don't you? 
                         He's back. Lord Voldemort has returned.
 
                         
<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         Send an owl to Azkaban, think they'll 
                         find they're missing a prisoner. 
 
                         
<character>BARTY JR</character>
                         I'll be welcomed back like a hero.
 
                         
<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         Perhaps. Personally I've never had much 
                         time for heroes.
 
              <setting>INT. ASSEMBLY ROOM</setting>

<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         (Speaking to all pupils) Today we acknowledge 
                         a really terrible loss. Cedric Diggory 
                         was as you all know, exceptionally hard 
                         working, intricately fair minded. And 
                         most importantly a fierce fierce friend. 
                         I think therefore you have the right 
                         to know exactly how he died. You see, 
                         Cedric Diggory was murdered by Lord 
                         Voldemort. The ministry of magic does 
                         not wish me to tell you this. But not 
                         to do so I think would be an insult 
                         to his memory. Now the pain we all feel 
                         at this dreadful loss reminds me, reminds 
                         us that while we may come from different 
                         places and speak in different tongues, 
                         our hearts beat as one. In light of 
                         recent events the bonds of friendship 
                         we made this year will be more important 
                         than ever. Remember that and Cedric 
                         Diggory will not have died in vain, 
                         you remember that. And we'll celebrate 
                         a boy who was kind and honest and brave 
                         and true right to the very end.
 
              <setting>INT. BEDROOM</setting>

              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> is sitting on a bed, Dumbledore walks in.

<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         I never liked these curtains. Set them 
                         on fire in my fourth year, by accident 
                         of course. I put you in terrible danger 
                         this year<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> I'm sorry.
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Professor, when I was in the graveyard 
                         there was a moment... um... when Voldemort's 
                         wand and mine sort of connected.
 
<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         Priorium Contatum. You saw your parents 
                         that night didn't you? They reappeared.
 
                         
              <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> nods.

<character>DUMBLEDORE</character>
                         No spell can reawaken the dead<character_ref>Harry</character_ref> 
                         I trust you know that. Dark and diffiult 
                         times lie ahead. Soon we must all face 
                         the choice between what is right what 
                         is easy. But remember this, you have 
                         friends here. You're not alone.
 
              <setting>EXT. HOGWARTS</setting>

               There's a large crowd gathered, the pupils are going home. Viktor 
               Krum gives Hermione a kiss and hands her some paper.
 
<character>VIKTOR</character>
                         Write to me. Promise.

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         Bye.

               Ron is sitting alone. The french sisters approach him, they both 
               in turn give him a kiss on the head.
 
<character>FLEUR</character>
                         Au revoir Ron.

               The Beauxbatons girls leave in uniform, the crowd applauds. The 
               Durmstrang boys leave too, shaking hands as they go.
 
<character>RON</character>
                         Do you think we'll ever just have a 
                         quiet year at Hogwarts?
 
<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         No.

<character>HARRY</character>
                         No I don't think so.

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         Everything's going to change now isn't 
                         it?
 
<character>HARRY</character>
                         Yes.

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                         Promise you'll write this summer. Both 
                         of you.
 
<character>RON</character>
                         Well I won't. You know I won't!

<character>HERMIONE</character>
                        <character_ref>Harry</character_ref> will won't you?

<character>HARRY</character>
                         Yeah. Every week.

               They look over the balcony, the flying horses pulling a carriage 
               head off into the distance. The Bulgarians' ship goes underwater.
 
          FADE OUT.
</root>